### **BALA KRISHNAN M**

# **Quality Assurance Engineer Trainee**

Mobile: +91-7449066501 Email id: krishbala282@gmail.com

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Quality engineer trainee with 1 year 10 months of experience in the field of automobile industry, seeking a challenging position in a reputed organization to expand my learning, knowledge and skills, while making a significant contribution to the success of the company

### PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

Work experience 1 : Quality control inspector (Research and development department)

Employer : Turbo Energy Pvt Limited

Period : 06/2019-10/2020

Customer : BorgWarner Turbo Systems, Tata, Mahindra.

Designation : Apprenticeship Trainee

### **Description:**

To monitor the incoming and outgoing products or materials for a company and tasked with conducting tests, analysing measurements and overseeing production process.

- Able to read product drawings, control plans and specifications to understand the requirements of products.
- Measure product dimensions, examine functionality and compare the final product to the specifications as per drawings.
- Document preparation and inspection by completing detailed reports.
- Supervise the production process.
- Able to conduct material test on Torsional and Tensile tests, brinnel and Vickers hardness test, able to handle automatic measuring instruments like Rondcom, Contour, surfcom.
- Resolve quality related issues in a timely manner.
- Knowledge in PPAP Documents, Geometrical Dimensions and Tolerances.

Work experience 2 : Quality assurance inspector.
Employer : ABI Showatech India Pvt limited.

Period : 01/2021-06/2021 Customer : Garret, Honeywell Designation : Trainee Engineer

# **Description:**

To make sure that the product of industry meets the prescribed quality standards.

- Inspecting and auditing products to ensure that they meet quality standards.
- Conducting dimensional audits and process audits
- Conducting tests for quality control of products.
- Able to handle Automatic measuring instruments like Coordinate Measuring Machine, Roundness Measuring Machine, Surface Finish Tester,
- Knowledge in Production Part Approval Process.

#### **TECHNICAL TRAININGS**

- One day workshop training on Sri City Siemens Technical Skill Development Institute

### PROJECTS HANDLED IN COLLEGE

- Designed and fabricated 'wear test on rigid sleeves using brake drums' which is used for testing the wearness of sleeve materials at different rpm and different loads by using two wheeler brake drum.
- Extraction of Biodiesel from Palm oil distillate and performance test on diesel engine. the Biodiesel used as alternate fuels for fossil fuels.

# **SOFTWARE PROFICIENCY**

AutoCAD,CREO,CATIA. : Products design(basic knowledge)
Microsoft Office : Word, Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint

### **INTER-PERSONAL SKILLS**

- Good communication skills
- Quick learner
- Ability to work under pressure
- A good team player and having good managerial skills

## **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFIATIONS**

Bachelor of Engineering : MECHANICAL ENGINEERING (2015-2019)

CGPA : 7.32 (FIRST CLASS)

College: : RMK COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY,

University : ANNA UNIVERSITY, CHENNAI.

### PERSONAL DETAILS:

Father Name : Munirathinam C

Mother Name : Saradha M

Date of Birth : 11-06-1998

Nationality : Indian

Rationality : Indian Gender : Male

Marital Status : Unmarried

Languages Known : English, ,Tamil and Telugu.

Mobile Number : +91-7449066501

Permanent Address : 108, North Street, kallalangkuppam, Kodaikkal post,

Sholinghur taluk, Ranipet district, Tamil Nadu-631102.

### **DECLARATION**

"I hereby declare that the above information is true to best of my knowledge".

Place:	(BALA KRISHNAN M)
Date:	